Now listen, yo!
People put your guns up
First I'll run dat
Run around and shoot them
Brand new sound, yes still survival
Here comes the sound boy, live in this world
Intelligence, strength, and luck are swirling, flow
My swelled mind is candid
One punch to Banner in Savannah
An easy knockout, bam bam bam
One time for your mind, live through this
Around the world
It haunts me, the pain of the past
Around the noble god are borrowed things
When the seed that's sown flowers, whose is it
Live and fire the arrow of faith, more more more
There is no peace where you're going
Come on, stand up, don't give up the fight
Now, yes, this instant, die die die
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
Shit...
（計(けい)）ハァハァ ハァハァ…
No wonder my suit is damaged...
（計）そりゃ オシャカにもなるか
もしかしたら…
Maybe I could...
Please Live
It hurts...
（室戸）痛(いて)え… 口 痛えよ…
My mouth hurts!
I have to fight with my own strength!
I have to go back alive!
自分の力で戦わなくちゃ
生きて帰らなくちゃ
（電子音）
（計）使える
I can use this!
Two of them? No way!
（電子音）
（計）２つ？ まさか…
C'mon you two, stay alive...
２人とも 生きててくれ
Please Mr. Furuta... Mika... Stay alive!
頼む 古田(ふるた)さん みか
生きててくれ　今行くから
I'm coming right now!
（みか）
人なんて殺したくないけど―
Killing someone is the last thing
I want to do, but I have to go back!
帰らなくちゃ
（首を絞める音）
アアッ… 痛えっつってんだよ！
You're hurting me...
（室戸）やったぜ
（悲鳴）
ざけんじゃねえ
Give me a fuckin' break!
Don't get all cocky just because
some dude wants to sleep with you!
ちょっと ヤラせろって
言われたぐらいで―
うぬぼれてんじゃねえ！
俺に勝てると思ってたのかよ？
What made you think you could beat me?
（計）やめろ！
（室戸）あっ…
Stop it!
（銃撃音）
（計）室戸 お前(めえ)な
Can't you think of anything but killing people?
人殺す以外に
考えることねえのかよ？
Kurono Alien!
（室戸）玄野(くろの)星人！
（計）俺は生きて帰りたい
I want to go back alive,
and I'm going to bring Mika back alive, too!
（計）みかも生きたまま連れ戻す
Huh? Are you fuckin' stupid?
ああ？ てめえ バカじゃねえのか？
ぶっ殺してやるぜ
どこだ？ 出てこい！
I'll kill you! Where are you? Come out!
I want to let you live!
（計）俺は生かしたいんだ！
All you want to do is kill, but I'm not like you!
（計）
殺したいてめえとは違うんだよ！
（室戸）うるせえ！
Shut up!
You're just full of shit!
（室戸）そういうのはさ
きれい事っていうんだよ
隠れてないで出てこいよ
玄野星人！
Stop hiding! Just come out, Kurono Alien!
What, you're scared?
（計）怖いのか？ 人殺しのくせに
You're telling me a murderer is scared?
You son of a bitch!
（計）てめえ！
何人殺したら気が済むんだ！
How many people do you have to kill?
（室戸）アア… もう やめてくれ
芝居してるんじゃありません
Stop it...
I'm not even acting right now.
This isn't an act!
芝居なんかじゃないですよ
お願いしますから 助けてください
I'm begging you! Please help me!
There's a whole bunch of people
who'd still be alive right now
（計）てめえが
そんな芝居さえしなきゃな…
if it hadn't been for that stinking act!
死なずに済んだヤツが
たくさんいたんだよ！
If only if we worked together sooner!
もっと早く
みんなで協力してりゃ…
YOU'RE the one who killed everyone!
みんなを殺したのは
てめえなんだよ！
You son of a bitch!
このバカ野郎！
Please sto...
（室戸）乱暴は やめ…
（蹴る音）
Are you all right?
（計）大丈夫か？
（みか）
ダメ… 目が見えなくなってきた
No... I'm losing my sight...
But you know what?
でもね
（計）えっ？
I did it...
私 やったの
I was too scared to fight back then,
and had so many regrets about it...
（みか）あのときは怖くて
全然 抵抗できなくて…
後悔してて…
But I did it this time.
でも 今度は やったよ
あいつに力いっぱい…
I fought back against him
with everything I had...
So I have no more regrets...
だから もう後悔してないよ
You can still make it! If you can just stay alive...
まだ助かる 死にさえしなけりゃ
時間内に あのマンションに
戻れれば 元に戻れる
and make it back to the apartment in time,
you'll be as good as new!
Really?
ホント？
（計）だから諦めるな！
So don't give up!
Okay.
Kurono...
玄野君…
（計）うん？
Mr. Furuta died... for me...
古田さん 私のために…
死んじゃった
But he tried his best to convince that kid...
（みか）でも…
一生懸命 説得しようとして…
He tried to help others... until the very end...
最後まで 人のために…
I didn't know there were still adults like him...
（みか）あんな大人の人…
まだ… いたんだね
Mr. Furuta...
古田さん…
Please...
（みか）お願い
（計）えっ？
You go back alive, okay?
君は… 生きて帰って
な… 何言ってんだ？
絶対 一緒に帰るんだ
What are you talking about?
We're going back together no matter what!
ウッ！
（室戸）玄野星人 捕まえた！
I got you, Kurono Alien!
もう逃がさないよ
（計）む… 室戸 お前…
I won't let you get away this time!
Muroto! Why you...
（首を絞める音）
ああ そうだよ
That's right. I've been waiting for
you to let his guard down.
玄野星人が油断するの待ってたんだ
See, I'd be terrified if you got away again!
また消えられたら怖いからさ
（計）ウウッ！
I'm just a coward, you know!
俺は ホントは気が弱いんだよ
I've been scared of just about
everything ever since I was a kid.
（室戸）子供のころから
世の中の何もかも怖かったんだ
Do you have any idea what it's like
分かるか？
目を覚ましてる間ずっと―
誰かに殴られるんじゃないかって
おびえてる気持ち
to spend every waking moment
in fear of someone hurting you?
（室戸）分かるか？
（計）ウウッ…
（室戸）痛えか？ みっともねえな
それぐらいで痛がってんじゃねえよ
Does it hurt? You're pathetic.
C'mon, this shouldn't be
enough to hurt you at all.
I was... I was...
俺なんか… 俺なんかな！
（首を絞める音）
ちくしょう！
Goddamn it!
（室戸）復讐(ふくしゅう)してやるんだ
俺をさんざん痛めつけたヤツらに
I'm going to get revenge...
Revenge against everyone who
used to slap me around!
Revenge against the adults who used me...
利用した大人たちに…
あいつらの耳をそいで
足を折って 指つぶして
I'm going to rip their ears off!
Break their legs!
Crush their fingers!
体バラバラにしてやるんだ！
（蹴る音）
Cut them to pieces!
（計）殺して どうなる？
What will you change by killing them?
Huh? Is that the thing?
（室戸）
あっ… これか？ 消えちまうの
Were you going to disappear?
You were going to disappear again so you
could beat me up like earlier, weren't you?!
また消えて 俺をボコボコに
するつもりだったのかよ？
ふざけんな！ やっぱ てめえも
あいつらと同じじゃねえかよ！
Stop fuckin' with me!
You're no different from them!
That's not going to happen!
（室戸）そうはさせるかよ
（踏みつぶす音）
All of you look down on me.
どいつもこいつも
白い目で見やがってよ
悪いのは俺じゃねえ　あいつらだ
I'm not the one who's wrong! It's all of them!
It's the society that forced them to be that way!
あいつらを
あんなにした世の中だろうがよ！
It's not my fault that I kill people!
俺が人殺すのは
俺のせいじゃねえんだよ
Kajiura forced me to be his
errand boy so I had no choice!
（室戸）梶浦(かじうら)に
無理やりパシリにさせられて―
しかたなく やってたんですよ
本当なんです
That's the truth!
（計）ウッ…
（室戸）お願いします
Please... Let's stop!
もう やめましょうよ
もうイヤです
I don't want to do this anymore...
I was in pain...
つらかったんだ
I used to be so afraid of my mother
coming home from the store.
買い物に行った おふくろが
家(うち)に帰ってくるのが怖かった
I really was afraid she was going to kill me.
ホントに いつ殺されるか
分からなかったんだ
One time my dad told me my mother
was a good, kind woman,
（室戸）
あるとき 親父(おやじ)が言ったんだ
“母さんは優しくて いい女だ”
and that she'd never to such a thing to me.
“お前に
そんなことをするはずがない”って
But when I told him how I felt about her,
だけど そう言った親父が
俺が ちょっと言っただけで―
he beat me up until he broke my bones!
俺の骨が折れるまで
殴りやがったんだぞ！
Can you believe that?!
信じられっか？
骨が折れるまでだ！
Until he broke my bones!
（計）ンンッ… 関係ねえ
I don't give a damn.
What makes you think it's okay to kill people
just because you were abused as a kid?
子供のころ
ひでえ目に遭ったら―
人殺していいのかよ？
（計）
世の中のせいにして済むのかよ？
Will it solve anything if you blame it on society?
（室戸）
やめてください！ 近寄らないで！
Please don't do this! Don't come near me!
Will it solve anything if you blame it on society?
Don't you come near me!
近寄るな！
俺の服は まだ壊れてないんだぞ
My suit is still intact! I could
crush your body if I want to!
てめえの体なんか
バキバキにできんだぞ！
殺すのが楽しいんだろう？
You love killing, don't you?
Then do it, you goddamn murderer!
やれよ この人殺し！
I didn't kill them because I wanted to!
俺は 殺したくて殺したんじゃ…
俺のせいじゃねえ
It's not my fault!
ウソつけ！ てめえは人殺しだ
Stop lying! You're a murderer!
Gantz isn't the sickest one. It's people like you!
本当に狂ってるのはガンツじゃねえ
てめえみてえな人間だ！
You did it because Kajiura forced you to?
Don't give me that crap!
梶浦に命令されたから？
ふざけんな！
So is it okay to kill people
if someone asks you to?
命令されたら
人殺していいのかよ？
Answer me, damn it!
答えろ！ おら！
Isn't it the way it is in countries that are at war?
（室戸）だって 戦争してる国じゃ
そうじゃないですか
Don't you watch the news?
テレビのニュース
見たことないんですか？
（計）ああ？ 何だよ？ それ
Huh? What the hell are you talking about?
You know, like in those Middle Eastern
countries? Palestine or Chechnya or whatever...
中東や
パレスチナやチェチェンとか…
俺も よく分かんないけど 軍隊が
メチャメチャ人殺してるでしょうが
I don't know all the details,
but the military over there has been
killing people like crazy!
I thought they were killing people
because they were ordered to!
あれって命令されたから
殺してるんじゃないんですか？
How about America?
アメリカだって
イラクに攻めてって―
They've been attacking Iraq and
killing tons of people, right?
メチャメチャ人殺してんだろう
The number of people they've killed is
nothing compared to what I've done!
俺の殺した人数とは
比べもんになんないじゃんか
They killed more than ten thousand innocents
just so they could kill a few terrorists, right?
テロリスト数人 殺すために―
普通の人 １万人以上
殺してんじゃねえのかよ？
（室戸）それを何だよ？
So how can you blame me for
killing just a few people?
たった何人か殺した俺が
こんなに責められんのかよ！
（室戸）それって何なんだよ？
What's up with that?!
Give me a fuckin' break!
冗談じゃねえよ！
（殴る音）
It's none of your business!
（室戸）関係ねえんだよ！
世界中で人殺し やってんだ
People are killing each other all over the world!
俺が何人殺したって
そんなの大したことじゃねえんだよ
So why's it such a big deal
if I kill people, too, huh?!
それを何だよ？
Are you any different?!
You've killed people, haven't you?!
（室戸）てめえは違うのかよ？
殺したんじゃねえのかよ？
I've never killed a person!
俺は 人間は殺してねえ！
So then it's okay to kill
as long as they aren't human?!
人間じゃなきゃ殺していいのかよ？
Many of my friends...
（計）仲間を…
Many of my dear friends
were killed, so that's why I...
大切な仲間を何人も殺されたんだ
You idiot!
バカか！
それだって立派な殺しだろうが！
That's still killing!
I just killed them before they got me!
俺だって やられる前に
やってきただけだろうが！
I only tried to kill you because Gantz told me to!
ガンツが
てめえを殺せって言ったから―
やろうとしただけだろう？
So you'll kill if you're ordered to?
だから
命令されたら殺していいのかって？
そういう てめえだって
今までガンツに命令されて―
Looks who's talking!
Haven't you been killing all this time
just because Gantz told YOU to?
さんざん
殺してきたんじゃねえのかよ！
（計）ンンッ… だから 俺は…
Like I said, I've never...
Oh, Kajiura wasn't a human?!
（室戸）
梶浦は人間じゃねえのかよ？
ハァ… ンンッ…
梶浦は 人間やめちまってた
Kajiura forgot that he was a human...
To keep him from killing
everyone else, I had to...
みんなを生かすためには…
ヤツだけは…
So you're going to kill me, too?
For those who have died, right?
じゃ 俺も殺すのかよ？
死んじまった みんなのためにか？
ウソだろう？
That's bullshit!
You'll kill me for your own sake
because you want to go back alive!
生きて帰りたい自分のためだろう！
同じじゃねえかよ 俺と！
Isn't that the same as me?
Kajiura told me that you and I
have the same kind of eyes.
（計）梶浦が言ってたぜ
俺と てめえの目が似てるってよ
I never want to be grouped together with you!
（計）てめえなんかと
一緒にされたくねえんだよ！
Then how come you didn't kill me sooner?
（室戸）だったら なんで
とっとと やらなかったんだよ？
Oh yeah, I should've!
And I was going to earlier!
（計）
ああ そうだ　さっきは やれたよ
But people like Kato and Mr. Furuta
helped me to decide...
けどな
加藤(かとう)や古田さんと決めたんだよ
We're going back together!
みんなで帰ろうって
その中には ムカつくけど―
It really pisses me off, but that means you, too!
てめえだって入ってんだよ！
You know what?
いいか？
殺しゃいいってもんじゃねえんだよ
Killing isn't always the way to go!
I...
（室戸）俺は…
（計）来いよ
So come with me.
時間がないんだ
We don't have much time.
I hate listening tO lectures!
俺は説教が大嫌いなんだよ！
（計）ウッ…
室戸
Muroto!
（計）室戸！
（スイッチを押す音）
Muroto!
止まれ！ ンンッ！
Damn it! I can't stop it!
チッ… 止まらねえ！
Help me!
（室戸）助けてくれ！
No, there has to be a way to get out
of this labyrinth and I'm sure of it!
（古田）いや この迷宮を
出られる方法が きっとある！
Let's all go home together alive!
What do you say?
みんなで生きて帰ろうじゃないか
I know that, Mr. Furuta!
分かってるって 古田さん！
（計）室戸！
Muroto!
You're going to be okay!
（計）
大丈夫だ　死ななきゃ元に戻るんだ
You'll be returned to normal
if you can stay alive now!
（計）室戸…
Muroto...
This suit is great! I wasn't hot at all!
すげえよ このスーツ　熱くねえよ
I understand how it works now.
使い方 分かってきたぜ
これさえあれば 何も―
I don't have to be afraid of anything
as long as I'm wearing it!
怖くねえよ
（計）ウウッ！
（計）ウワッ！
The world sure is crazy, huh?
（室戸）世の中 どうかしてるぜ
A murderer like me gets to survive
instead of a soft ass like you!
てめえみてえな お人よしより―
俺みてえな人殺しが
生き残れるんだからな
You're just like that old geezer!
（室戸）
てめえも そのオヤジと同じだよ
You're going to die regretting
you ever put trust in others!
人を信じたことを
後悔して死ぬんだ！
You're wrong!
（計）違う！ 後悔もしねえし
死にもしねえんだよ！
I'm not going to have any regret...
or die for that matter!
What... what is this?
（室戸）な… 何だ？
殺さないって言ったよな
俺を殺すのかよ？
You said you never kill people, right?
But you're going to kill me?
I wish I could just kill you!
ぶち殺してやりてえよ
But you're still human, so I'll send you up there.
けどな お前は まだ人間だ
だから送ってやるぜ
（発射音）
Stop it! Help me!
（転送音）
やめてくれ！ 助けてくれ！
It was the right thing to do, wasn't it, Mr. Furuta?
（計）これでいいよな？ 古田さん
Are you still alive? Hey!
（計）生きてるか？ おい！
返事してくれ！ おい！
Say something! C'mon!
（みか）ウッ… 思い出した
（計）えっ？
I remember now...
You're... from...
君 あのときの…
From when? What is it? Mika!
“あのときの” 何だ？ みか！
That moment we were all watching you...
（みか）あのとき 私たち…
見てたよ
What are you saying? When was that?
（計）何言ってんだ？ だから
あのときって何のことだよ？
We... saw... you...
見てたの…
at the train station...
駅で…
The train station...
駅… 駅って…
You mean, the subway station?
地下鉄のことか？
おい しっかりしろ！
C'mon, stay with me!
Stay with me! We'll go back soon!
（計）
しっかりしてくれ！ すぐ帰れる
So you saw us at the subway station?
地下鉄で俺たちを見てたのか？
Don't die on me! C'mon, Mika!
死なないでくれ　おい みか！
What are you doing, Gantz?!
（計）何やってんだ？ ガンツ！
It must be over now! So hurry up
and start the transfer!
もう終わったんだろう？
早く… 早く転送しろよ！
I know we can still make it! Gantz!
まだ間に合うんだろう？ ガンツ！
（計）えっ？ 何だよ？ これ
What the hell is this?
You still want to do this, Gantz?
（計）
まだやろうってのかよ？ ガンツ
Gantz, you son of a bitch...
（計）ガンツ てめえ…
You're going to take it this far, huh?
ここまで やるか？
May I have you attention please?
（アナウンス）
お客さまに お知らせいたします
Due to heavy rain, there has been a
significant delay in train schedule.
本日の大雨に伴いまして 現在
ダイヤが大幅に乱れております
Mika? I see... you were here.
みか…
We apologize for the inconvenience and
thank you very much for your patience.
そうか ここに いたのか…
えっ？ 野崎(のざき)？ 古田さん…
Nozaki? Mr. Furuta?
（加藤）計ちゃん？
Kei?
加藤！
Kato?
Kei, it's you, right?
計ちゃんだよな？
Trying to act cool, huh? What an idiot!
（計）
バ～カ　なにカッコつけてんだ？
What do you think you can do on your own?
（計）１人で何ができんだよ？
１人で何ができんだよ？
What do you... think you can do on your own?
（計）１人で…
何が？
The next train will be arriving
at platform two shortly.
（アナウンス）
まもなく２番線に電車がまいります
Please stay behind the white line...
白線の内側にお下がりください
...on my own...
１人で…
We've struggled and bled so much...
こんなに苦労して血ぃ流して―
俺たちは
どこに帰ろうっていうんだ？
What kind of world are we trying
to go back to anyhow?
A world where no one will help a homeless man,
who's fallen onto the train tracks?
線路に落ちたホームレスを
誰も助けようとしない世界へか？
A world where a homeless man,
何もしてないホームレスが
頭をかち割られる世界へか？
who never did anything to anyone,
gets his head smashed open?
Hey, run!
おい 走れ
Mr. Furuta, what can I do on my own?
（計）古田さん 俺１人で何が…
I... I really think you're great. I'm serious.
（岸本(きしもと)）私… 玄野君
すごいって思ってる ホントに
You're a lot different from Kato, but...
加藤君とは感じが違うけど　けど…
It's supposed to come in next week.
At the bookstore by the train station...
（聖(せい)）
来週 届くんだ　駅前の本屋さん
Kei, I don't know what's going to happen to me...
（聖）計君
私 どうなるか分かんないから―
But if anything does, would you be
willing to pick the book up for me?
そうなったら
取りに行ってくれないかな？
お願い 君は生きて帰って
Please...
You go back alive, okay?
Kato...
（計）加藤… １人で何ができる？
What can I do on my own?
What can I...
俺…
１人で… 何ができるんだ？
do on my own?
You can do it, Kurono...
（みか）
できるよ 玄野君　君なら きっと
I know you can do it.
でも １人で何が？
But still... what can I do on my own?
We were all watching you then,
though we couldn't help you...
（みか）あのとき 私たち 見てたよ
助けられなかったけど
だから 今度こそ…
But this time...
Please live...
（みか）お願い 生きて
Live for us!
私たちの分まで
Kei, are you all right?
計ちゃん 大丈夫か！
Kurono...
（みか）玄野君
We'll be fine as long as you live.
君が生きていてくれれば
私たちは大丈夫だから
Many of them must've died...
（みか）
きっと いっぱい死んだんだよね
People who were so important to you...
君の大事な人たちも
You can do it, Kei!
（加藤）頑張れ 計ちゃん！
Please, Kei!
お願い 計ちゃん
Thank you for all your help.
（女性）
いろいろ ありがとうございました
You told me to find it on my own,
so I tried very hard.
（女性）あなたに
自分で探せと言われたもので―
一生懸命 探したんです
Thanks to you I was able to find it.
おかげさまで見つかりまして
I wish you good luck, too...
あなたも どうぞ頑張って
I won't die! I will never die, Gantz!
（計）死なねえよ
俺 絶対 死なねえよ！
ガンツー！
Bang!
（計）バン！
We all start out as pure and innocent babes
Even if you taste the bitter fruit,
don't be discouraged, walk straight
I know it's in the past, but the rain still stings
I'm lonely as floating ice
I kiss your thin finger
And remember you crying
Even if this is the end
I won't forget your last kiss
I won't forget
I won't forget his kiss